myteachingstation.com 2018-09-26

# Privacy Statement | MyTeachingStation.com

This Privacy Statement discloses the privacy practices for MyTeachingStation.com website. We are committed to protecting your online privacy. Please read the following to learn what information we collect from you (the "User" or the "End User") and how we use that information. If you have any questions about our privacy statement, please contact us via the Website.

PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT CAREFULLY. BY ACCESSING OR USING OUR WEBSITE, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT YOU HAVE READ, UNDERSTAND, AND AGREE TO BE BOUND TO ALL THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY STATEMENT AND OUR WEBSITE TERMS OF USE. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THESE TERMS, EXIT THIS PAGE AND DO NOT ACCESS OR USE THE WEB SITE. 

  1. **Changes to Privacy Statement**

We may change this Privacy Statement at any time by posting the revised Privacy Statement in the "Privacy Statement" section of the Website. The revised Privacy Statement is effective immediately when posted on the Website. It is the responsibility of each User to review the Website and the Privacy Statement periodically to learn of any revisions to this Privacy Statement. Your continued use of the Website after the effectiveness of such revisions will constitute your acknowledgment and acceptance of the terms of the revised Privacy Statement.

  2. **Types of Information Collected and Uses of Collected Information**

We collect two types of information about our Website Users: Personally Identifiable Information and Non-Personally Identifiable Information.

    * **Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally Identifiable Information is information that identifies a specific End User. When you engage in certain activities on the Website, such as creating an account, subscribing to our newsletters, posting a comment, submitting content and/or posting comment in our community forum, filling out our contact or any other form in the Website (collectively, "Identification Activities"), we may ask you to provide certain information about yourself. It is optional for you to engage in an Identification Activity. If you elect to engage in an Identification Activity, however, we may ask you to provide us with certain personal information about yourself, such as your first and last name, mailing address, email address, phone etc. Depending on the activity, some of the information we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some is identified as voluntary. If you do not provide the mandatory information for a particular activity that requires it, you will not be permitted to engage in that activity.

We may use Personally Identifiable Information to improve our marketing and promotional efforts, our product offerings, and to tailor your experience to the best. For example, if you send an email or post a comment we may use your comments and feedback to tell others about our services, and may post your comment in our marketing materials or on our Website. We may also use Personally Identifiable Information to troubleshoot, resolve disputes, accomplish administrative tasks, contact you, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities.

    * **Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

Non-Personally Identifiable Information is information that does not identify a specific End User. This type of information may include things like the Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") of the website you visited before coming to our Website, the URL of the website you visit after leaving our Website, the type of browser you are using and your Internet Protocol ("IP") address. We, and/or our authorized Third Party Service Providers, may automatically collect this information when you visit our Website through the use of electronic tools like Cookies.

We use Non-Personally Identifiable Information to administer the Website, analyze trends, gather demographic information, comply with applicable law, and cooperate with law enforcement activities.

  3. **Release of Personally Identifiable Information**

We will not share your Personally Identifiable Information with other parties except as provided below:

We may share your information for our Protection and the Protection of Others. We may also disclose Personally Identifiable Information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law or a court order; enforce or apply this Privacy Statement, our Website Terms of Use or other agreements; or protect the rights, property or safety of the Website, its Users or others.

  4. **Release of Non-Personally Identifiable Information**

We use Third Party Service Providers to track and analyze Non-Personally Identifiable usage and volume statistical information from our Users to administer our Website and constantly improve its quality. Please note that this is not Personally Identifiable Information, only general summaries of the activities of our Users. Such data is collected on our behalf, and is owned and used by us.

  5. **Updating and Correcting Information**

We believe that you should have the ability to access and edit the Personally Identifiable Information you provide us. You may change any of your Personally Identifiable Information by contacting us via our Website. Please indicate your name, address and email address, and what information you would like to update when you contact us. You may change some of our Personally Identifiable Information by clicking on My Profile section of the Website.

We encourage you to promptly update your Personally Identifiable Information if it changes. You may ask to have the information on your account deleted or removed.

  6. **User Choices on Collection and Use of Information**

As discussed above, you can always choose not to provide information, although it may be required to engage in a certain activity on the Website.

As a condition of creating an account or subscribing to our newsletter, we will send you Administrative and Newsletters emails. We will send you information regarding your account activity as well as updates about our resources. You cannot opt-out of Administrative Emails. "Administrative Emails" relate to a User’s activity on the Website, and include emails regarding a particular User’s account, requests or inquiries. In contrast to Administrative Emails, however, you do have a choice with respect to Newsletters Emails. Newsletters Emails advertise our resources and services. If you do not want to receive Newsletters Emails from us, you may elect to opt-out of receiving Newsletters Emails at any time after registering by contacting us via the Website, or by hitting the "unsubscribe" button at the bottom of any of our e-mails. When contacting us, please indicate your name, address, email address, and what Newsletters Emails you do not want to receive.

  7. **Security of Information**

We take security seriously and take numerous precautions to protect the security of Personally Identifiable Information. You can access your Personally Identifiable Information on our Website through a password and your username. This password is encrypted. We recommend that you do not share your password with anyone. In addition, your Personally Identifiable Information resides on a secure server that only selected personnel have access to.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we employ commercially reasonable security measures to protect data, we cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted to or from the Website, and are not responsible for the actions of any third parties that may receive any such information. For more detail information on our disclaimer, please review our Terms and Conditions located at www.theteachingstation.com/terms-and-conditions.

For your safety and protection, your credit card information is not stored on our servers. Our payment gateway provider, keeps this information encrypted and secure on your behalf.

  8. **Data Tracking**

Cookies. To facilitate and customize your experience with the Website, we store cookies on your computer. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a User’s computer for record-keeping purposes which contains information about that User. We use cookies to save you time while using the Website, remind us who you are, and track and target User interests in order to provide a customized experience. Cookies also allow us to collect Non-Personally Identifiable Information from you, like which pages you visited and what links you clicked on. Use of this information helps us to create a more user-friendly experience for all visitors. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you may be able to modify your browser settings to decline cookies. Please note that if you decline or delete these cookies, some parts of the Website may not work properly.

Other Tracking Devices. We may use other industry standard technologies like pixel tags and web beacons to track your use of our Website pages and Newsletters, or we may allow our Third Party Service Providers to use these devices on our behalf. Pixel tags and web beacons are tiny graphic images placed on certain pages on our Website, or in our emails that allow us to determine whether you have performed a specific action. When you access these pages or open or click an email, pixel tags and web beacons generate a Non-Personally Identifiable notice of that action. Pixel tags allow us to measure and improve our understanding of visitor traffic and behavior on our Website, as well as give us a way to measure our promotions and performance.

  9. **Privacy Statement of Third Party Websites**

This Privacy Statement only addresses the use and disclosure of information we collect from you. Other websites that may be accessible through this Website have their own privacy statement and data collection, use and disclosure practices. If you link to any such website, we urge you review the website’s privacy policy. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties.

  10. **Miscellaneous Privacy Issues**

Public Areas. We provide a commenting system areas on our Website where you can publicly post a comment. This information may be accessible by other users and may appear on other websites or web searches, and therefore this information could be read, collected, and used by others. No e-mail address is ever published when you login or post as a guest, however if you include your e-mail address in the comment itself you may receive unsolicited messages. We have no control over who reads your postings or what other users may do with the information you voluntarily post, so please use caution when posting any personal information.
